Why do you make me wait?
Come on!
Howl!
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
- Oh. my God!
- What?
- Take it easy.
- I was trying to do everything right.
- Don't just become excited.
I thought if I stayed away from City
Hall. I wouldn't have bad luck again.
- You're making me feel guilty.
- I'm marrying your brother.
All right. I'm guilty.
I confess.
The wedding's in a couple of weeks.
You're invited.
How come you didn't be like him
and be with your mother in Palermo.
- She don't like me.
- You don't get along with anybody.
- What did you do?
- What did I do?
- You ruined my life.
- That's impossible!
It was ruined when I got here.
You ruined my life.
- No. I didn't.
- Yes. you did!
You got them bad eyes
like a gypsy.
I don't know why
I didn't see it yesterday.
Bad luck. That's it.
Is that all I'm ever gonna have?
I should have taken a rock
and killed myself years ago.
I'm gonna marry him. Do you hear me?
Last night never happened.
You and I are gonna take this
to our coffins.
- I can't do that.
- Why not?
I'm in love with you.
Snap out of it!
- I can't.
- Then I must never see you again...
and the bad blood will have to stay
between you and Johnny forever.
- And you won't come to the wedding.
- I'll come to the wedding.
- I'm telling you. you can't come!
- He wants me to come.
That's because he don't know.
Now wait a minute.
Honey. listen.
All right. I won't come
to the wedding. provided one thing.
- What?
- You come with me tonight to the opera.
- What are you talking about?
- I love two things.
I love you. and I love the opera.
If I can have the two things that I love
together for one night...
I would be satisfied
to give up--
Christ.
To give up the rest of my life.
All right.
- Meet me at the Met.
- All right.
- Where's the Met?
- You gotta--
Bless me. Father.
for I have sinned.
It's been two months
since my last confession.
What sins have you to confess?
Twice I took the name
of the Lord in vain...
once I slept with the brother
of my fiance...
and once I bounced a check
at the liquor store...
- but that was really an accident.
- Then it's not a sin.
But what was
that second thing you said?
The one about once I slept
with the brother of my fiance?
- That's a pretty big sin.
- I know.
- You should think about this.
All right. For your penance.
say two rosaries.
Be careful. Loretta.
Reflect on your life.
All right.
- Hi.
- Where you been?
- I don't want to talk about it.
- Just like your father.
I lied to him.
- He thinks you came home last night.
- Thanks.
What's the matter with you?
- Cosmo's cheating on me.
- What?
- Yeah.
- How do you know this?
- A wife knows.
- Mom. you don't even know.
You're just imagining it.
He's too old.
I won't be home for dinner.
I feel great.
I got no sleep.
but I feel like Orlando Furioso.
You were a tiger last night.
And you were a lamb.
as soft as milk.
Shh! Lower your voice.
They'll hear you in the back.
So what? The pleasure of marriage
is you sleep with the woman...
- you don't worry about nothing.
- Be quiet. Raymond!
- How about a date tonight?
- What's the matter with you?
We'll eat some pasta.
We'll roll around a little.
- What got into you?
- I really don't know.
That crazy moon Cosmo sent over.
Hi. Aunt Rita.
Hi. Uncle Raymond.
Hey. there!
You with the stars in your eyes
- What's the matter with him?
- You got me.
You see that moon last night?
- What moon?
- Did you see it?
Listen. I gotta go. okay?
I'll take the deposit to the bank...
but I'll come back tomorrow
and do the books.
Sure. You got a date.
What are you talking about.
you fool?
Her fiance's in Palermo!
What date?
Right.
- I just got a lot of things to do.
- You got all that wedding stuff.
Yeah.
That's romantic too.
Isn't it romantic
Frankie.
make me a bowl of minestrone!
What's the matter with you?
You look crazy.
- I got a lot on my mind.
- What?
- I got a lot--
- Don't tell me that! What's the matter?
- I don't want to talk about it!
- You look like you're nuts!
I don't want to talk about it.
Take out the gray.
I have been wanting to do this
for three years.
Let me show you some magazines.
And you're gonna need a manicure.
yes.
You take her. Batina.
She's gonna take out the gray.
Yeah. and someone will have
to do the eyebrows.
- Look. Something nice and soft.
- Wait a minute.
- Has anybody here been to the opera?
- Not me.
- Bellissima without those ugly grays.
- It's fantastic.
- You ever been to the opera?
- No. have you?
Batina. you ever been to the opera?
- This is the color I would use.
- La Boheme?
- I've never been there.
- You're going to the Met?
Yeah.
She came in when she turned 40
and her husband left her.
- Bye-bye.
- Okay.
Wow. Look at that.
Careful.
I'm home!
Don't everybody answer
at the same time. Hello!
You look beautiful.
- Your hair.
- Yeah. I had it done.
You look beautiful too.
Thank you.
I said I'd go to the opera with you.
but that's all.
Come on. let's go in.
- Look at that.
- Isn't it something?
Wow. Thank you.
For what?
I don't know.
For your hair.
For your beautiful dress.
I don't know. It's been a long time
since I've been to the opera.
- So. where are we sitting?
- Come on.
Here we go.
- So. who's coming?
- Just me. I want to eat.
Okay.
I got a table for you right now.
- This all right?
- Fine.
- Enjoy your meal.
- Thanks.
- You dining alone tonight?
- Hello. Yeah.
Let me have a martini.
no ice. two olives.
Very good.
I'm trying to explain to you
how I feel.
Every time I tell you how I feel.
you tell me how you feel.
- That's not much of a response.
- It's the only response I got.
- You want something to eat?
- Not now. I'll wait.
Very good.
I really hate it
when you use that tone with me.
Like you're above it all
and isn't it so amusing.
- But it is. isn't it?
- Not to me.
This is my life. no matter how comical
it may seem to you.
I don't need some man standing above
the struggle while I'm rolling in mud.
I think you like to roll around
in the mud and I don't.
That's fair. isn't it?
Now why--
Oh. my.
Sorry about that. folks.
She's a very pretty
mental patient.
No. don't.
Please. don't mind me.
Just do me a favor
and clear her place.
Get rid of all evidence of her.
and bring me a big glass of vodka.
Absolutely.
- I'm sorry if we disturbed you.
- I'm not disturbed by you.
My lady friend
has a personality disorder.
She's just too young for you.
Thanks. comrade.
It's nothing.
Too young? I just got that.
You know how to hurt a guy.
- How old are you?
- None of your business.
I'm sorry. That was rude.
Would you like to join me
for dinner?
Are you sure?
I'd be delighted.
I hate to eat alone. It's amazing
how often I end up doing just that.
- Signora Castorini.
- Oh. yes.
- Your minestrone.
- Thanks. Bobo.
-What do you do?
-I'm a communication professor at N.Y.U.
- That woman was a student of yours?
- Sheila? Yeah. she was.
Is.
Was.
My mother had an old saying.
You want to hear it?
- Sure.
- Don't shit where you eat.
I'll remember that.
- What do you do?
- I'm a housewife.
- How come you're eating alone?
- I'm not eating alone.
- May I ask you a question?
- Yeah. go ahead.
Why do men chase women?
- Nerves?
- I think it's because they fear death.
Maybe. You want to know
why I chase women?
I find women charming.
I teach these classes
I've taught for a million years.
The spontaneity went out of it
for me a long time ago.
I started out excited about something.
wanted to share it.
Now it's rote.
a multiplication table.
Except sometimes
I'll be droning along.
I'll look up.
and I'll see a fresh...
beautiful. young face.
And it's all new to her.
I'm just this great guy
who's brilliant and thinks out loud.
When that happens. when I look
out there among those chairs...
and see a young woman's face...
and see me in her eyes...
the way I always wanted to be.
maybe once was...
I ask her out for a date.
It doesn't last long.
A few weeks.
A couple of precious months.
Then she catches on that
I'm just this burnt-out. old gasbag...
and she's as fresh and bright...
and full of promise
as moonlight in a martini.
At that moment. she stands up and throws
a glass of water in my face...
or some action to that effect.
What you don't know about women
is a lot.
That's not what I hear.
- What would you like?
- Two white wines.
Yes. sir.
I'd like two glasses
of champagne.
Canadian Club and ginger ale
and Dubonnet on the rocks. please.
- What's that?
- This was done by Marc Chagall.
- As you can see. he was a great artist.
- Kind of gaudy.
He was having some fun.
- They get some turnout for this stuff.
- It's the best thing there is.
I like parts of it.
but I don't really get it.
You haven't once said
you like my dress.
I like your dress.
It's very bright.
Will you hold this?
Thanks.
- May I walk with you a ways?
- Sure.
Thanks.
- Do you live far from here?
- Just up there.
- You knew that man?
- Yes.
That was so awful.
- "Awful"?
- Beautiful. Sad.
- She died.
- Yes.
I couldn't believe it.
I didn't think she was gonna die.
- I knew she was sick. but--
- She had TB.
I know. She was coughing
her brains out. right?
And still she had to keep singing.
- Shall we go now?
- Pop?
What are you doing here?
Wait for me by the doors. Mona.
Excuse me.
- What'd you do to your hair?
- I had it done.
- What are you doing here?
- Who's that guy? You're engaged.
- And you're married.
You're my daughter.
I won't have you act like a putana.
- And you're my father--
- All right.
- I didn't see you here.
- I don't know if I saw you here.
Let's get out of here.
I'll buy you a drink.
That woman
was not my mother. okay?
That's my house.
- You mean the whole house?
- Yes.
My God. it's a mansion.
It's a house.
I live in a one-bedroom apartment.
What exactly
does your husband do?
- He's a plumber.
- That explains it then.
Temperature's dropping.
- I guess you can't invite me in.
- No.
- People home.
- No. I think the house is empty.
I can't invite you in
because I'm married...
because I know who I am.
- You're shivering.
- I'm a little cold.
You're a little boy.
and you like to be bad.
We could go to my apartment.
You could see how the other half lives.
I'm too old for you.
I'm too old for me.
That's my predicament.
Good night.
Can I kiss you on the cheek too?
Sure.
I'm freezing.
Good night.
Anything else. folks?
I think that's it. Al.
- See you. Al.
- See you. Carmine.
- What do you want to do now?
- I want to go home.
- Good night. Al.
- Take it easy. Ronny.
God. it's cold.
It smells like snow.
You know. my mother guessed
that my father was seeing somebody.
That Mona-- I mean.
she's some piece of cheap goods.
Who am I to talk?
- What's the matter?
- How can you ask me that?
- You're making me feel guilty.
- You are guilty. I'm guilty.
Of what?
Only God can point the finger.
I know what I know.
And what do you know?
You tell me my life.
I'll tell you yours.
I'm a wolf.
You run to the wolf in me.
That don't make you no lamb.
You're gonna marry my brother.
Why you want
to sell your life short?
Playing it safe is just about
the most dangerous thing...
a woman like you could do.
You waited for the right man
the first time.
Why didn't you wait
for the right man again?
- Because he didn't come.
- I'm here.
You're late.
- This is your place.
- That's right.
- This is where we were going.
- Yeah.
You know. we had a deal.
You told me if I came with you
to the opera...
then you'd leave me alone forever.
I came with you.
Now I'm gonna marry your brother...
and you're gonna
leave me alone forever. right?
A person can see where
they've messed up in their life...
and they can change
the way they do things...
and they can even change
their luck.
So maybe my nature
does draw me to you.
That don't mean
I have to go with it.
I can take hold of myself.
I can say yes to some things...
and no to other things
that are gonna ruin everything.
I can do that.
Otherwise. you know...
what good is this stupid life
that God gave us?
- Are you listening to me?
- Yeah.
Everything seems like nothing
to me now.
I guess I want you in my bed.
I don't care
if I burn in hell.
if you burn in hell.
The past and the future
is a joke to me now.
I see that they're nothing.
I see they ain't here.
The only thing that's here
is you and me.
I want to go home.
I'm going home.
- I'm freezing to death.
- Come upstairs.
I don't care why you come.
That's not what I mean.
Loretta. I love you.
Not like they told you love is.
And I didn't know this either.
But love don't make things nice.
It ruins everything.
It breaks your heart.
It makes things a mess.
We aren't here to make things perfect.
The snowflakes are perfect.
The stars are perfect.
Not us.
We are here to ruin ourselves...
and to break our hearts...
and love the wrong people...
and die.
I mean.
the storybooks are bullshit!
Now. I want you to come upstairs
with me and get in my bed!
Come on.
Nineteen Cranberry Street.
Brooklyn.
Got it.
Hold it!
- How much?
- Twenty-five.
- Twenty-five dollars?
- Yeah.
Hold it.
Hi.
I'm sorry to call so late.
- Moving in?
- No. I came right from the airport.
Come on in.
Can you wake up Loretta?
I need to talk to her.
She's not home yet.
Take off your coat
and come in the living room.
I'll make you a drink.
I want to talk to you.
- Thank you. Where is she?
- Out.
I don't know where.
So. what are you doing here?
You're supposed
to be in Palermo.
That's what I came to tell Loretta.
There's been a miracle.
A miracle?
Well. that's news.
My mother's recovered!
You're kidding.
The breath had almost totally
left her body.
She was as white as snow.
Then she completely
pulled back from death...
and stood up...
and put on her clothes...
and began to cook
for everyone in the house:
the mourners and me and herself.
She ate a meal
that could choke a pig.
- That's incredible.
- Yes.
Hi. Pop.
Oh. my God.
Is he all right?
My father-in-law
has this wrong idea...
in his head.
Listen. Johnny...
there's a question
I want to ask.
I want you to tell me the truth.
if you can.
Why do men chase women?
There's the Bible story.
God took a rib from Adam
and made Eve.
Now maybe men chase women
to get the rib back.
When God took the rib...
He left a big hole there...
a place where there used
to be something.
And the women have that.
Now maybe...
just maybe...
a man isn't complete
as a man...
without a woman.
Why would a man need...
more than one woman?
I don't know.
Maybe because he fears death.
That's it.
That's the reason.
I don't know!
Thank you
for answering my question.
Hello. Mr. Castorini.
- Where you been?
- I don't know. Rose.
I don't know where I've been
or where I'm going.
All right?
You should have your eyes open.
- I have my eyes open.
- Yeah?
Stick around.
Don't go on any long trips.
I don't know what you mean.
I know you don't.
That's the point.
- I'll say no more.
- You haven't said anything.
And that's all I'm saying.
- Cosmo.
- What?
I just want you to know...
no matter what you do. you're
gonna die just like everybody else.
- Thank you. Rose.
- You're welcome.
I'm going to bed now.
- I'm going.
- Good.
He doesn't like you.
but thank you for answering my question.
- You don't know where Loretta is?
- No idea.
Mrs. Castorini. will you tell Loretta
that I'll come by in the morning?
We need to talk.
- Okay. I'll tell her.
- Thank you.
Watch it. The house.
- What the hell happened to you?
- I really don't know where to start.
- Your hair's different.
- Ma. everything is different.
- Are you drunk?
- No. are you drunk?
No. but I have a hangover.
- Where's Pop?
- Upstairs.
Johnny Cammareri showed up last night.
- What? He's in Sicily.
- No more he's not.
- He's with his dying mother in Sicily.
- She recovered.
- She was dying.
- It was a miracle.
This is modern times. There ain't
supposed to be miracles no more.
I guess it ain't modern times
in Sicily.
He came right from the airport
to talk to you.
You got a love bite
on your neck.
He's coming back this morning.
What's the matter with you?
Your life's going
down the toilet!
- Cover up that thing! Put makeup on!
- All right!
Ma. okay. fine!
But you got to help me!
- Hurry up!
- Oh. my God.
You get it.
Answer the door! Mother?
Hi. Is Loretta home?
Come on in.
It's not Johnny!
- Is Johnny here?
- No. but he's coming.
Good. We can get this out
on the table.
Hi. I'm Ronny.
Johnny's brother.
I'm Rose Castorini.
- It's nice to meet you.
Got a love bite
on your neck.
- Your mother's recovered from death.
- Good.
- We're not close. I'm not really moved.
- You gotta get outta here.
- I'm here to meet the family.
- Really. you gotta get outta here.
Anyone want some oatmeal?
- No. Ma.
- Yes. Mrs. Castorini.
- I would love some oatmeal.
- No. we don't want any oatmeal!
- Take your coat off. Sit down.
- Ma! What? This is a--
- Thanks. Ma.
- You're welcome.
Cosmo. this is Ronny.
Johnny's brother.
It's very good to meet you.
I have a feeling
this is going to be just delicious.
- You're Johnny's brother?
- Yeah.
- Don't look at me like that.
- Hi. Pop.
What's the matter. Pop?
I am old.
The old are not wanted.
And if they say it.
they have no weight.
But. my son. I must speak.
You must pay for the wedding
of your only daughter.
You break your house
through pride.
There. I've said it.
It's okay. Pop.
If she gets married.
I'll pay for the whole thing.
Now you talking.
Let's eat.
- Have I been a good wife?
- Yeah.
I want you to stop seeing her.
And go to confession.
A man understands one day
that his life is built on nothing...
and that's a bad. crazy day.
Your life is not built on nothing.
- It's Johnny. I'll get it.
- I'll get it.
- I think I should tell him.
- I'll tell him.
- What am I gonna tell him?
- Tell him the truth.
- They find out anyway.
- You're right. Pop.
Why aren't you at the store?
Do you have something
you want to tell us?
We just come from the bank.
Yeah?
My God! The bank!
I forgot to make the deposit!
- She's got it!
- I knew she had it!
- We didn't know what to think.
- I forgot!
It was so weird yesterday.
- I know. I'm sorry.
- Then we went to the bank and no bag.
- We never suspected you.
- Would anyone like some coffee?
- Yes. coffee.
- That's a good idea.
- What's with this?
- I'll tell you later.
- I forgot to make their deposit.
- Here. sit down. Have some coffee.
- So what are we doing?
- Waiting for Johnny Cammareri.
- My name's Ronny.
- Johnny's brother.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Rita Cappomaggi.
- Hi.
- Raymond Cappomaggi. Rose's brother.
Someone tell a joke.
I'll get it.
I thought Johnny was in Palermo.
It's Johnny Cammareri.
- Have you come to make peace with me?
- Yes.
But you may not want to.
Ronny. of course I want to.
But. Johnny. your mother was dying.
How did she recover?
I told my mother we were to be married.
and she got well right away.
- I'm sure she did.
- It was a miracle.
- Thank God.
- Yeah.
- I have something I have to tell you.
- And I have something to tell you...
- but I must talk to you alone.
- I need my family around me now.
- I can't marry you.
- What?
If I marry you.
my mother will die.
What the hell are you talking about?
We're engaged.
- What are you talking about?
- I'm talking about a promise.
- He proposed!
- Because my mother was dying.
Now she's not!
You're 42 years old.
She's still running your life.
You are a son
who doesn't love his mother!
You are a big liar!
Because I have a ring right here.
- I must ask for that back.
- All right. the engagement is off.
- In time you will see this is best.
- In time you'll drop dead...
and I'll come to your funeral
in a red dress!
What?
Will you marry me?
- What?
- Where's the ring?
Can I borrow that ring?
Thanks.
Will you marry me?
Yes. Ronny. In front
of all these people. I'll marry you.
- Do you love him. Loretta?
- Ma. I love him awful.
God. that's too bad.
She loves me.
What's the matter. Pop?
I'm confused.
To Loretta and Ronny!
Come on. There.
Come.
- Your brother is here and you're--
- I don't want any.
You're part of the family.
Don't you realize?
Come on. please.
Everybody. come on.
Glass in hand.
To the family!
Subtitles By
Captions. lnc. Los Angeles
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today